<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-11-07T00:14:09+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Balancing Pond</title><subtitle>Another Lemon-and-Bismuth, pronto!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">To Amsterdamse Bos</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/amsterdam/2016/05/08/amsterdamse-bos.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="To Amsterdamse Bos" /><published>2016-05-08T22:14:46+02:00</published><updated>2016-05-08T22:14:46+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/amsterdam/2016/05/08/amsterdamse-bos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/amsterdam/2016/05/08/amsterdamse-bos.html">&lt;p&gt;Sunday, hot. Despite cold, decide to step outside. Spent last night 
contemplating where to walk today. Considered one of Amsterdam’s three sewage 
farms (RWZI), preferably Amsterdam West, that being the most extensive. 
Probably too far. Then, noticed a near continuous stretch of green going from 
my place close to the banks of the Amstel, along Amstel, Amstel Park and out 
to Amsterdamse Bos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set off around 1pm, back around 7:30pm. Struck by the relaxed, fair-like and 
altogether quaint atmosphere of Amstel Pk. Quite busy, then step across 
&lt;em&gt;Roud Brug&lt;/em&gt; and into the wonders of the 60s social housing of Amsterdam Zuid. 
Today it is like a ghost town - hardly a soul in site. The high white blocks 
are laid out around large open spaces - high boulevards of trees, waterways 
and planted walkways - a winning combination of prestressed concrete 
parkitecure and lush greenery. These deeply peaceful spaces fill me with the 
same sense of academic bliss as one finds in the most secluded of Cambridge 
college quadrangles. Onwards to the Bos. Lying before the entrance to the Bos 
from this approach are the highly decorated coffins of the Pharaohs of 
Amsterdamse Bos, the most notable of whom was Tootin’ Cartoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgur.com/r5iV4Ot&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/r5iV4Ot.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 600px;&quot; alt=&quot;Tootin Cartoon&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;	
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&quot;&lt;i&gt;Here lieth Tootin' Cartoon&lt;/i&gt;&quot;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reached the Bos, pass possible location of the nude spa (note for future 
reference), and head to the long long water of Bosbaan. I could watch the 
giant KLM planes taking off over the water for hours - blue planes in a blue 
blue sky over a deep blue water. I notice a heron perched close to the 
water’s edge. Another chance for the perfect heron shot. I know I will get it 
one day, perhaps today is that day? I’m crouching down, still, eye firm to 
the lense when I hear laughter from behind me. As I move away, it then dawns 
on me that the party behind think I’m taking shots of the topless woman 
sunbathing a few feet to the left. No! It’s the heron! Honest! Time to move 
on and hide my shame in the depths of the Bos…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgur.com/iFMm2si&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/iFMm2si.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px;&quot; alt=&quot;The Infamous Heron&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;	
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&quot;&lt;i&gt;The Infamous Heron&lt;/i&gt;&quot;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…Following paths inwards, I notice a distinct area of raised ground on 
the horizon - no, it can’t be! Surely this must be a mirage! It’s a…hill! 
First hill I’ve seen in this country, let alone city. I race onwards to 
this ridge of high ground. Summit. Questions. Is this a real hill or man 
made? It rises unnaturally steeply and falls away as such on the other 
side. Lots of stonework about. I find an information board containing some 
old black and white photos of men with shovels, and an old vista showing 
how it used to look– something akin in style to the stretch down to the 
water at Versaille or in Vienna. I knew it was too good to be true. Time 
to head back. Sapped of energy given the cold. Just manage to limp home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgur.com/wv6tP1Y&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/wv6tP1Y.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 600px;&quot; alt=&quot;The Infamous Hill&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/a&gt;	
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&quot;&lt;i&gt;The Infamous Hill&lt;/i&gt;&quot;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Sunday, hot. Despite cold, decide to step outside. Spent last night contemplating where to walk today. Considered one of Amsterdam’s three sewage farms (RWZI), preferably Amsterdam West, that being the most extensive. Probably too far. Then, noticed a near continuous stretch of green going from my place close to the banks of the Amstel, along Amstel, Amstel Park and out to Amsterdamse Bos. Set off around 1pm, back around 7:30pm. Struck by the relaxed, fair-like and altogether quaint atmosphere of Amstel Pk. Quite busy, then step across Roud Brug and into the wonders of the 60s social housing of Amsterdam Zuid. Today it is like a ghost town - hardly a soul in site. The high white blocks are laid out around large open spaces - high boulevards of trees, waterways and planted walkways - a winning combination of prestressed concrete parkitecure and lush greenery. These deeply peaceful spaces fill me with the same sense of academic bliss as one finds in the most secluded of Cambridge college quadrangles. Onwards to the Bos. Lying before the entrance to the Bos from this approach are the highly decorated coffins of the Pharaohs of Amsterdamse Bos, the most notable of whom was Tootin’ Cartoon. &quot;Here lieth Tootin' Cartoon&quot; Reached the Bos, pass possible location of the nude spa (note for future reference), and head to the long long water of Bosbaan. I could watch the giant KLM planes taking off over the water for hours - blue planes in a blue blue sky over a deep blue water. I notice a heron perched close to the water’s edge. Another chance for the perfect heron shot. I know I will get it one day, perhaps today is that day? I’m crouching down, still, eye firm to the lense when I hear laughter from behind me. As I move away, it then dawns on me that the party behind think I’m taking shots of the topless woman sunbathing a few feet to the left. No! It’s the heron! Honest! Time to move on and hide my shame in the depths of the Bos… &quot;The Infamous Heron&quot; …Following paths inwards, I notice a distinct area of raised ground on the horizon - no, it can’t be! Surely this must be a mirage! It’s a…hill! First hill I’ve seen in this country, let alone city. I race onwards to this ridge of high ground. Summit. Questions. Is this a real hill or man made? It rises unnaturally steeply and falls away as such on the other side. Lots of stonework about. I find an information board containing some old black and white photos of men with shovels, and an old vista showing how it used to look– something akin in style to the stretch down to the water at Versaille or in Vienna. I knew it was too good to be true. Time to head back. Sapped of energy given the cold. Just manage to limp home. &quot;The Infamous Hill&quot;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Minchenden Oak</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/london/2014/11/28/minchenden-oak.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Minchenden Oak" /><published>2014-11-28T22:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-11-28T22:30:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/london/2014/11/28/minchenden-oak</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/london/2014/11/28/minchenden-oak.html">&lt;p&gt;On 28th November 2014 I walked from my parent’s house in north London in a 
direct line due north for one mile or so. Following this transect, I noticed 
it cross right through a churchyard, and in fact right through the heart of a 
massive ancient oak tree. This is known as the 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.minchendenoak.org/&quot;&gt;Minchenden Oak&lt;/a&gt;. Minchenden, I believe, is 
the old name of the area, derived from an old estate/family–the local school 
I attended as a child used also to be called Minchenden. The oak has stood on 
this site for hundreds of years and is considered holy by some (I included, 
not least due to the exact northern alignment with my childhood home).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgur.com/t6M8wGG&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/t6M8wGG.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px;&quot; alt=&quot;Minchenden Oak&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;figcaption&gt;The Minchenden Oak&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this, I continued north along the transect. This took me up into Trent 
Park, where I found a few sodden mushrooms, including these delicious 
shaggy-caps, and a throne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgur.com/w8gTv7E&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/w8gTv7E.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px;&quot; alt=&quot;Shaggy caps&quot; /&gt;
   &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;figcaption&gt;Shaggy caps&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgur.com/gYC7SFQ&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/gYC7SFQ.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 400px;&quot; alt=&quot;Throne&quot; /&gt;
   &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;figcaption&gt;Throne of the late King of Trent Park&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">On 28th November 2014 I walked from my parent’s house in north London in a direct line due north for one mile or so. Following this transect, I noticed it cross right through a churchyard, and in fact right through the heart of a massive ancient oak tree. This is known as the Minchenden Oak. Minchenden, I believe, is the old name of the area, derived from an old estate/family–the local school I attended as a child used also to be called Minchenden. The oak has stood on this site for hundreds of years and is considered holy by some (I included, not least due to the exact northern alignment with my childhood home). The Minchenden Oak After this, I continued north along the transect. This took me up into Trent Park, where I found a few sodden mushrooms, including these delicious shaggy-caps, and a throne. Shaggy caps Throne of the late King of Trent Park</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Eastern Fringes of Cambridge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cambridge/2013/10/18/eastern-fringes-of-cambridge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Eastern Fringes of Cambridge" /><published>2013-10-18T00:39:09+02:00</published><updated>2013-10-18T00:39:09+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cambridge/2013/10/18/eastern-fringes-of-cambridge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cambridge/2013/10/18/eastern-fringes-of-cambridge.html">&lt;p&gt;If you look at a map of Cambridge, you will notice that the historic 
centre of the city is not in the geographical centre, but much further 
to the west, with vast suburbs mushrooming out to the east. My guess as 
to why this is would be primarily because the lands to the west of the 
city are largely College owned and so in some respects are protected green 
belt. Secondly because of the presence of the M11 which tightly skirts the 
western edge. Most students in the city seldom venture east, so I decided 
to take a look, and found some interesting sites…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/eastern-fringes-of-cambridge/IMG_20131017_111245.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cambridge-map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favourite types of walk is along long arterial roads - I like 
the way you don’t need to concentrate on navigating, so can just switch 
off and absorb the scenery. I apply this technique on Cherry Hinton Road, 
which is my travelator into Eastern Cambridge. I emerge in the suburb of 
Cherry Hinton, one of the numerous villages swallowed up by Cambridge’s 
relentless march east.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/eastern-fringes-of-cambridge/Photo0520.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cherry-hinton&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the source of the Cherry Hinton Brook (later Coldham’s Brook). 
Although Cambridge is often ridiculed for being flat, it is actually based
 at the foot of a chalk escarpment (lying to the south east), the very same
 which runs all the way through the Chilterns (Icknield Way) and down to the
 south coast (Ridgeway). As the chalk hits the impermeable clay of the low 
 lands, water is forced out in springs such as this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/eastern-fringes-of-cambridge/Photo0517.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;hinton-source&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chalk has a secondary purpose here - building material. Another thing 
you’ll notice about Eastern Cambridge is that large chunks of it are 
missing. The whole areas is pocked with chalk pits, some now filled with 
water. Several of the colleges were built from this very chalk - material 
taken from the east to build the west. The largest is located close to the 
spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/eastern-fringes-of-cambridge/Photo0513.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;chalk-pit-1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stepping into the chalk pit is like stepping back in time 150 million 
years. In the chalk you can see coloured strata, successive eras being 
laid down on top of each other. Recent excavations revealed iron-age 
settlements here. Standing in the middle of the pit is slightly horrifying; 
I’m feeling like a pterodactyl might swoop down and carry me off at any 
moment…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/eastern-fringes-of-cambridge/Photo0515.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;chalk-pit-2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Re-entering the present day on Limekiln Road, I decide to follow the Cherry 
Hinton Brook north through the Eastern Fringe. This takes me past two more 
huge chalk pits, disguised as great lakes. A lone Holiday Inn sparkles on 
the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/eastern-fringes-of-cambridge/Photo0521.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;holiday-inn&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Brook laces through suburbs and darts into an ever-narrowing allyway. 
Eventually I stumble out behind a Sainsbury’s Superstore building and 
follow the brook through the carpark and onwards to Coldham’s Common - a 
vast array of football and rugby pitches, the Hackney Marshes of Cambridge. 
Peering suspisciously over the bushes is a science park - this specie is 
ubiquitous on the Cambridge fringes; they radiate a paranoid energy into 
the landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/eastern-fringes-of-cambridge/Photo0526.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;science-park&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the scrub in the north part of the common, I emerge into the car park 
of the Abbey Leisure Complex - a sublime piece of liminal architecture. In 
the words of Iain Sinclair “since when did leisure become so complex?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/eastern-fringes-of-cambridge/Photo0528.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;leisure-complex&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brook continues past the Cambridge United Stadium - I contemplate the 
footfall of hundreds of supporters on the little footbridge over the brook, 
unaware of the water and its chalky history, passing slowly below them. 
About a year after this walk, in a very rare event, top dogs Manchester 
Utd were invited to play against Cam Utd. It was a classic David vs Goliath 
moment - I don’t remember who won, but I do remember the town swelling 
with Man-U fans on a Friday evening. I played pool with some of them in the 
Emporer on Hills Rd. They were pretty rowdy and possibly on drugs - the 
game was pretty tense, not because of the score, more because I thought I 
might get a pool cue to the head if I didn’t play my balls right…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/eastern-fringes-of-cambridge/Photo0533.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cam-utd&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brook now forms a buttcrack of green corridor between Barnwell and East 
Barnwell, which holds one of the jewels of the city: the Leper Chapel, 
founded 1125, one of Cambridge’s oldest buildings. Today this sits on the 
busy A1134, Newmarket Road. It gave rise to Stourbridge fair on neighbouring 
Stourbridge common, which was one of the largest fairs in Medievel Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/eastern-fringes-of-cambridge/Photo0537.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;lepel-chapel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before sunset I reach the confluence of the brook with the River Cam, 
a magical place to end a magical day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/eastern-fringes-of-cambridge/Photo0543.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;confluence&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">If you look at a map of Cambridge, you will notice that the historic centre of the city is not in the geographical centre, but much further to the west, with vast suburbs mushrooming out to the east. My guess as to why this is would be primarily because the lands to the west of the city are largely College owned and so in some respects are protected green belt. Secondly because of the presence of the M11 which tightly skirts the western edge. Most students in the city seldom venture east, so I decided to take a look, and found some interesting sites…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Northfleet to Brixton: A Topologically Non-Trivial Transect Through South London</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/london/2012/04/07/northfleet-brixton.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Northfleet to Brixton: A Topologically Non-Trivial Transect Through South London" /><published>2012-04-07T23:30:00+02:00</published><updated>2012-04-07T23:30:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/london/2012/04/07/northfleet-brixton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/london/2012/04/07/northfleet-brixton.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I embarked on this walk last year in April, a week after attending my grandfather’s funeral in Maidstone, Kent. My grandfather lived there happily with my 
grandmother for many years. I have many fond childhood memories of travelling to their’s in the back of my parent’s Citroen BX (later Toyota Carina) from our 
house in North London. Occaisonally we’d hoof it round the North Circular, A13, then Queen Elizabeth II Bridge. From here, staring down at the vast oil 
containers, I wondered what it would feel like to be down there staring back up at the vehicles high above on the bridge. But more often than not we’d drive via 
my dad’s work in Islington, then snake our way through Hackney picking up the A12 at Wick Rd. From here, as we approached the Blackwall Tunnel, I remember 
speeding passed Bromley-By-Bow tube station and remarking with my sister, “how on Earth can we still be in London?!” - this was miles from anywhere that was even 
vaguely familiar to us. So, you could understand my sister’s surprise when years later, on a separate walk to this one, I managed to walk here from our house in 
Ally Pally in a single morning. Leaving Bromley-By-Bow behind us we would descend into the Blackwall Tunnel, only to re-emerge into lands even more foreign and 
tantelising. As we surfaced on Bugsby Marshes, I remember craning my head in the late 90s to catch a glimpse of the Dome everyone was talking about going up 
behind us. Onwards then to Kidbrooke and through the Kidbrooke estate, which as far as I was concerned, was a remote outpost on the dark side of the Moon. I 
was fearful yet somehow enticed by it’s brutalist concrete structures and boarded up MDF windows. Beyond here, I was sure we were well out of London by now as 
the sign at the petrol station was for a place that I’m sure was up north somewhere - Mottingham. Even more unbeleivable it was then, when several miles of 
crampt dual carraige ways later (Eltham, Sidcup, Foot’s Cray), we at last ascended onto the M20 over a strange vale of woodland and I saw the “Welcome to Kent 
sign”. As I travelled this same route on the day of my Grandfather’s funeral, it occured to me that, not knowing anyone else in Kent, this may be the last time 
I ever travel through here. These unknown lands may remain unknown to me forever! Something had to be done. It was then, glancing out of my passenger seat 
window on the Swanley by-pass, that I vowed to find these places. My hope was that by walking to them on foot, they would become tangible, and an explorable 
part of the London I held in my mind…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was on the Thursday evening before Good Friday that I drew up my plans. As well as the towns of the A20, I wanted to take in the areas under the Dartford 
Bridge (I had heard tales of a gargantuan pylon down there that I wanted to investigate). My plan was to get out there quickly on public transport then slowly 
work my way back into London. The quickest way was to get a train from King’s Cross along the brand new High Speed 1 line to Ebbsfleet International, out there 
somewhere in the Thames Esturay. From here I would walk to the Dartford Crossing, then up the Thames, taking the River Darent into the upper M20 corridor. From 
here I would work my way through south-east London, back home. So, early on Friday morning, I was hurled out of London and onto 
flat eluvial planes of the Thames Esturay…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EBBSFLEET INTERNATIONAL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipPDlgDYOMyquIvGc0aPvcNIZCP211hSAZe0ocIWmaKelk5drX4WRBctANHnenaAIg?key=QkNpOENjSWRMRmJIY3NNNDRHV21Ta2FsYllsV2tR&amp;amp;source=ctrlq.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/EhTvF2UTkT9AjjJiPZsFrN9NIay5plW6EcQBhfukeg3ndUJ0EiaRSBbO4CzIBo9pHva4Ci3LsqTLlMwJUGL7gzGEE-2h6sSCfq-7C0BaR_kj0zC9O3TXeB5th3HTtsrDvXcF2mAaVLU&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I came to realise about Ebbsfleet, is that not only is it not a place that lives up to the grandness implied in “International”, it isn’t actually a place 
at all. After being the only person to alight from the train here, I wonder out of the station into a barren landscape of endless empty car parks. I eventually 
get my barrings, and pass under a railway bridge and into Northfleet, an old dock town on the outskirts of Gravesend. As local Danielle, who worked in The 
Plough pub (now greasy spoon Golden Grill), put it in a 2008 interview to the BBC “There is no Ebbsfleet, it’s a train station and that’s it. That’s all 
Ebbsfleet is. There is no Ebbsfleet”. Ebbsfleet is in fact a planned development of 40000 new homes on brownfield site in the vicinity of Northfleet. Already in 
places there are veins of yellow houses worming their way through the brownfield. I follow a sign pointing me towards the Thames Path, behind some warehouses. 
Getting narrower, hope I don’t meet anyone. Eventually, I can take a passage on the left which opens out onto the docks, but passage is boarded off with silver 
sheet metal and signs “footpath closed, WARNING do not enter”. I see the huge bodies of decaying dockyard cranes behind the awning, suddenly I’m engulfed with 
an intense sense of agoraphobic doom…I try to control the panic and head back into Northfleet. This feeling is one that I get again at various points in this 
landscape - it is not one designed on the human scale, everything is massive - huge trucks, collosal tankers, vast open spaces, towering bridges and pylons. I 
head out west across the bridge and into Swanscombe, another perculiar Esturary town, and descend towards the Thames into an expansive landscape of rubble and 
weeds…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipMtzcSQyVxjj7li5y2EHZQBVEXB5xs9rD6EIgk_XvtWEprSYxVYQZQLTmWxbC809g?key=Nm9abWlpdnNWMS0yc0V2TWlJRFZjbHBOaGlUVXZR&amp;amp;source=ctrlq.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-EpVNmqX1fAoIBA4mlKBrwnqEGg8vWHoO4bG4rd8dendRpyZ8cmeqio-ODgDupb0bqXhpAvZsDo-iVh4MHFc2COHnzoVwylCbHqDCM_TUs_oWKojBH0y9ZJyZnVAbcSCRyYp2TWz0dM&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THAMES GATEWAY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahead near the river I can see a pylon. It looks close, but it’s an optical illusion: this pylon is four times more massive than any I’ve ever seen. When I 
finally reach the base, I am standing next to something resembling the Eiffel Tower. On the far bank,  there is it’s twin, with thick electrical cables 
connecting the two high above the river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipNMzU5vFc79FeQtNtG3p1XhPiC9VUJoxxuis1lA2sHNyl1GCtQYwBcKpiRXHHskCg?key=TVRMWmt5bmQwa0Q0MFRJUENUWmpHblFxMjlHTER3&amp;amp;source=ctrlq.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/RqhBeYtWWEMSmJPaeR5StUwKWH27z_NP6SD3-mkskz28jy8zIM81G_c-f0Ow8LB2USQSyVV_TTvdstEvjRB3C2XXvu1se6QRXHSAJziFL_5wqDTiHjlCL_4__S7JvQL_C0nVZjyw-JA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onwards up stream to Greenhithe, past Ingress Abbey - built 1833, redeveloped by Crest circa 2002 (this is Deep Thames 
Gateway territory), the QEII bridge is getting ever closer. Eventually I am under the bridge, and again I am feeling like an ant about to be crushed. High above 
I hear the sound of endless streams of Tesco lorries vaulting the Thames. All I have for company down here is some rascist graffiti at the base of the concrete 
superstructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipNOh7ptsv0DS_oRHOxdh5jC9xo0Oh46p58kFwohNrPJTJTVi7taUHeoPxRs-ZR3VQ?key=X0VBSnFKNlpJTVlvbFk3UEp2UExxLWZETUxZcnFB&amp;amp;source=ctrlq.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/AuDu5ONUqSuRaNUKeamwNZlv5d7Mi-oubBhbqbwBhSHcu5RlS4JeLiiZ72GTOInVfeh1KK0DbitV0rt7ggVtnLZa1eWiyuvIq9G4SP2quiD856InxpKcDn7U0X65AT_IA7xo3zCvZLE&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on, I pass the Littlebrook Oil Fired Power Station and glimpse a fox through the mesh fence adorned with signs warning away those who 
have come in connection with the “Camp For Climate Action”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipN4nrK0-qAuWq5RVepbNkcjahnHFqZeplA1trUVzt6GGokShbDIQxRtfRWnB-iO1g?key=Tlp5REhMZm1XVkpxSDVVVEw2SzBxbnFfazdIMGZ3&amp;amp;source=ctrlq.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/RelzUeEkROK7mdbAyWI16iz3JI9qP7W5of3VJZzd4yHAlnKQ95WDr5j52MGzVbjJPMpvk6wu1t9YsH4XUsB5YyGw1rcydIbf5cCnpyg6OTHobYE1doK5mKi2V0l83imAOkPcb0QuU_k&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other side of the river I can see a massive tanker docked at Purfleet. There is a continuous 
stream of lorries surfacing from the hold. I watch for what seems like hours, transfixed, what on Earth could be inside all those containers? Coffins full of earth?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipOGQGDVHw23SITXKZm8TjLdgSNG7Lod9hB9VwTtPnwsdLtqERwU1u6Q_XZDksD3fQ?key=cnBaSnlWNjlqOTctMjBHVnI0SklhMy13cTdNLVFB&amp;amp;source=ctrlq.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/KvMH55KcOOosI6e6Ua94eoOi2jmnKS_hvPcp6tBPkuRjKNgA8AZJ7FEY1rfMX2qXBhVy5Pa-Ul3pBwWPUvb-8czgd0CZlGeVisjgrj5decwWzg12m58gWflPHQGC_s7uPddsFEMpW5I&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally I move on, 
though the lorries continue. Further upstream I come across a guy fishing; broad, bald, pink shirt, large hands. His wife is 
set back from the river sun bathing. This seems like a nice spot for a leisurely bit of fishing, though I wonder why he’s the one here? A few yards upstream I 
find my answer: the infamous Southern Outfall, where everyone’s shit from Brixton to Barnehurst is spewed out into the Thames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipNJWMWoYHoJVyQ9BvIKvpEeYYxTLnRz6UQ_Y1S53DBSlesgzxIgc-9PLFlqtpHvrQ?key=UVFvbllqNTNHUFNKS052NklFREE2MWRLY0VEakJ3&amp;amp;source=ctrlq.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/5DECE3Qumg2D-2Az9gAF-vjt_d4zdNw-Jfevl5dQIEY_RD8IKM2bW60PqFKqidrqZ98RZ2P5IaxZTZKm-0DKOajMzkcAQJT1UCyIu0HqzCa6aeB543ejaWWKBKlkv8K8KCdrLrYpOVU&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further up river my path is 
blocked by the introusion of the river Darent, it’s flood defenses visible over the flat landscape. I cut inland across the flood plains, now in the heat of the 
day, and stumble upon some strange decaying concrete structures - reminents of some by-gone industrial process?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipP2nVo1GKcgXZP5vY-uZFLSVWeeGd7rznkmM6A1kldUJml3iUmiRamkpU07MB_Kvw?key=emZmZDMxTUdhd1R0THQyeWQySGlEMExkN09VRzdn&amp;amp;source=ctrlq.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/5BDsH_-9TwgibmJS1PrehZaK9Tr7GgTcCq4Z9nixAUw3oDccfQdaAYYMdurT3QlB0mZLEHbRV8p_xIJU3mbduzNpHMJmhfhu529_Pd7FBPQG8d-u1nE7O-dWYXaaLcv-cOVhvfqK48I&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE CRAYS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having crossed the Darent I take a path passed a field full of junk being grazed by a couple of miserable donkies. I follow the Cray, a tidal tributary of the 
Darent choked with grey silt, past breaker’s yards, through Crayford and eventually come out in the grounds of Hall Place (founded 1537).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipMO19WIhp_GY4dTASbZvxPRxLpzan8E_7brFkD0AbhfqAcO5mddYTcsfFehsfmJag?key=SlhXQWktOW1BQzJtUDBvMVdnVlVjem04cFNzQ3JR&amp;amp;source=ctrlq.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/PvV_pOkrd_MjmLPvCCdXUGEvZfMnpG9dWhkekDuat5uiUOaRgr65kUXfwZFpSynFBPnkzrp2uu34goagAW8BBRncQWTRDxQsFAUheEQTqvBNJZpmVEQk4mIiIECfeg7c0LGtYUohOqU&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gardens were very fine indeed, and I took a much needed rest in the hot houses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipMFzrJNlIm3JfFQydS8gTohyXwW4Rut-eexLHSQQQdjUEJe5Jw7W1mQDinILsJ53w?key=NXZpN3F5TUNlT3lIYUYwME56RllWaG9yX3YwMzJn&amp;amp;source=ctrlq.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/ylZ5NQlcVagVY9PNwFPzCuwVC-oCBUcVcJ3-nq0jr2z6-me9TJbIt30x886UZEbL_xt80lJvbe-06oNNcVa3uRTJX_X0n1vPSDg4dxPy9-nbFgXJEiiZrH3N94147lrIaaxbL-r1-vg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onwards then to Bexley, and suddenly out into the countryside - I pass wondering chickens, riding schools, now into woods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipO9C-HwTFeYcKDcoqLwdWZEJzC3Qjqx5hkxDyVdJnwx6uUA0PctIx48FjJMtX-1Iw?key=eHd0cU5OUC1oRzdqRWgxYmVIbzNlc1lXbGZtWHVR&amp;amp;source=ctrlq.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/5peyz3DNiP8je1WCgoe4Uf1myPIFyj4IhIvg_MNbettQV9NVm6LLCvH0AdGEKe3m9n3-pm8uyHX9TpesmpHcuICnCG5vWIK4Xci8lM2ZbwfX6mX2O6gYbXqyg0pQxdrFSXOVCfGwZic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I emerge on a high point on rural Parsonage Lane - in the distance I see a great road crossing the wide valley - the A20? Yes! So I am 
here, down here, down in that strange vale - I’ve done it, I have travelled to other Worlds! I can see myself on the bridge, starring out of the passenger 
seat. I worry that if we make eye contact the universe may implode, so I quickly dive behind a hedgerow and shelter until the vehicle is out of view. Unsettled 
by my encounter I hot-foot it to Foot’s Cray, where I take refuge in the Deep Bar &amp;amp; Restaurant - a local hangout for Deep Topographers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipNPhWaWHwI24cLgr8NcnlSRRCCGAdxnbDGhCPbquCkYeqgB6-Rx4Us03aBID-UdVQ?key=TGNDbkI3bnRMdHQ5YWw0RWZ4QmpFZEo4Q0E4RG53&amp;amp;source=ctrlq.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/4jA1vkQ3MN24ar0woT_Dz1z1F7PltzwJGZsHyyPJqrU5MQkLUAYC8BHygTLkknkzmZwXJY_6HGIk-kyXhV7qxL82sZh6xhuRX0y-9g5DaJ_4qTlqpS7qymHdZV7aXAS2n9jBen4kNYs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Restored, I head down 
the A224 Cray Road only to be confronted by an impassable zone of roundabouts and roadside thickets - I have finally reached the A20. As a try to find a way 
through, wafts of punjent marajuana smoke emenate from an adjacent traveller site. Alas, there is no way through, and I am forced to trek west up the hard 
shoulder of the Sidcup-Bypass for about half a mile. I notice details that are not attainable at 60 mph: strange mock Tudor dwellings that can only be reached 
directly from the road side, unknown nature reserves (Scadbury Park). Finally I reach dry land at the Junction with the A222, work my way inland to MAIN ROAD, 
a long road taking me into further unknown suburbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipPSJsmuWYxUlkizG2PPnJLcj2EcdC7GHaxvpk5ZDtHuEOut6t4th8VPq6Lsyw6J0Q?key=cmFZTUw1WEJMQ3ZZNG5haUp5eDBCNTdublJXQmdB&amp;amp;source=ctrlq.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/If6qFIHXVLZ-gHhqjfvz6p-jfTkKJtB8LBArB3yrKr6G9MY_FXoGSQhTMXkhAacw5AoLA2JzQ0mRykaXC3sUGZcilopPpCXYpOkSpugMy8AjXhbREvNYDzQxqhT2-2Y4yC9wZA-xPfw&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FURTHER UNKNOWN SUBURBS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere on my trudge along here I pass into a trance…somewhere between New Eltham and Mottingham I am suddenly struck with hunger. The options aren’t 
looking great. I settle for an Indian take-away near the petrol station. My feet are sore now and the sun is starting to retreat. Huddled under a raincoat, I 
tuck in to my fluorescent chicken-tikka massala in some municipal park, hoping no one sees me. I have a quick check of the A-Z and head on through Eltham. 
Eventually I see something familiar - the Kidbrooke Estate. I have come at an interesting time - the whole estate is under massive redevelopment - the old Moon 
base is being replaced by something more hi-tech - dwellings fit for 21st century living. There are only a few of the old buildings left standing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipOikT57tai5x4xlNRuAjfAZOZ2pIVldxYPkwwlX12mNQ96G1CTzlpbEFrOgJFUUMw?key=QXRSSl84S2VtOWNtUXphajduZTI0QmVzaWpjVWVB&amp;amp;source=ctrlq.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/0UyCx7qNeAtOVDSAFTFrxvqsDfeaKWktUa4YteUqrS7MWvDjrSR2zB23zAVUVi8kNX8t3QkmngRlKDC87JkubQn0cVyYXxIlSXSv6tuWMVqz-qb1fOJuX3Adw-_MH-rUlH4JVYzxFgk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This place 
doesn’t feel safe, - I pick my way through half demolished council blocks, searching for a way out - I take my chances down a narrow allyway hoping I don’t meet 
anyone. I’m nearly at the out when my heart sinks - I hear voices coming from the other end - with no choice I plough on. As emerge from the other end ready to 
run, I almost collide with two prams being pushed by a pair of yummy mummys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORMHOLE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I seem to have fallen through some sort of worm-hole and landed in Hampstead. The streets are lined with Jaguars and 4x4s. The houses are detached and have 
columns. Where am I? As I walk down the leavy street, I consult my A-Z. It appears I am in Blackheath. The Highgate of the South.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipOUARz_9MTMLWYY_I-Y8RbPEkEtyTURmXblcaLKRD33qe_u7RG9sqClmZ5Zvqb5fQ?key=OUt6S2JNZy1LXzhoM0NzRFlCU3F5U1RBR3NLbXNR&amp;amp;source=ctrlq.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/ynS5SgaKgwZTm6C_aKCXSbqe6WAU9EihHVE-kk_9j4R2baNqKg37LKQHVzdv0Nyoslq7sjg8TNJOB0mfZk8tUeNkUQ8G7HmlWPapljaL3Ylt29oFTxMQA79wqlRKvX4Z8LwTPBRh3rQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As twilight approaches, I 
climb up to the heath, another site connected to the Camp For Climate Action, and gaze out across the city. I am planning to meet a friend in Brixton Market for 
a drink later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipOEhZ3QP-pJwZKD-NB3Cjo6OAkWT4OVcycfAKtHEG-13q4KDyNWz6mzCytusf7CXg?key=UnRLeXVwNU93cG10d1NWX25YallHMkZMX1JrWUln&amp;amp;source=ctrlq.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/qKs7LJiDmCYtY-FqMaHm7CRqLBJKLafEcjj4IYRRfy8siuTHhhTuvcEfcJpGHrPryMUAvgjMTzZHeS30luI9WMhZOlHqCTv2GBVVRljVK7Ou-KJDDaE2hCewgEW1zRBq1w691urSEOY&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having come this far by foot, I resolve to make Brixton by 9pm. I set off west down Shooter’s Hill, sticking to the main road all the way as it 
lacings through the inner-city districts of South London. As I recall, somewhere around Deptford a large blister on my ankle popped, considerably slowing 
progress. Somehow I limped on, and reached the market before 10pm, being just over 30 miles from Northfleet. In the days afterwards, both of the nails on my big 
toes turned black. I have since bought new walking boots.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">INTRODUCTION I embarked on this walk last year in April, a week after attending my grandfather’s funeral in Maidstone, Kent. My grandfather lived there happily with my grandmother for many years. I have many fond childhood memories of travelling to their’s in the back of my parent’s Citroen BX (later Toyota Carina) from our house in North London. Occaisonally we’d hoof it round the North Circular, A13, then Queen Elizabeth II Bridge. From here, staring down at the vast oil containers, I wondered what it would feel like to be down there staring back up at the vehicles high above on the bridge. But more often than not we’d drive via my dad’s work in Islington, then snake our way through Hackney picking up the A12 at Wick Rd. From here, as we approached the Blackwall Tunnel, I remember speeding passed Bromley-By-Bow tube station and remarking with my sister, “how on Earth can we still be in London?!” - this was miles from anywhere that was even vaguely familiar to us. So, you could understand my sister’s surprise when years later, on a separate walk to this one, I managed to walk here from our house in Ally Pally in a single morning. Leaving Bromley-By-Bow behind us we would descend into the Blackwall Tunnel, only to re-emerge into lands even more foreign and tantelising. As we surfaced on Bugsby Marshes, I remember craning my head in the late 90s to catch a glimpse of the Dome everyone was talking about going up behind us. Onwards then to Kidbrooke and through the Kidbrooke estate, which as far as I was concerned, was a remote outpost on the dark side of the Moon. I was fearful yet somehow enticed by it’s brutalist concrete structures and boarded up MDF windows. Beyond here, I was sure we were well out of London by now as the sign at the petrol station was for a place that I’m sure was up north somewhere - Mottingham. Even more unbeleivable it was then, when several miles of crampt dual carraige ways later (Eltham, Sidcup, Foot’s Cray), we at last ascended onto the M20 over a strange vale of woodland and I saw the “Welcome to Kent sign”. As I travelled this same route on the day of my Grandfather’s funeral, it occured to me that, not knowing anyone else in Kent, this may be the last time I ever travel through here. These unknown lands may remain unknown to me forever! Something had to be done. It was then, glancing out of my passenger seat window on the Swanley by-pass, that I vowed to find these places. My hope was that by walking to them on foot, they would become tangible, and an explorable part of the London I held in my mind… It was on the Thursday evening before Good Friday that I drew up my plans. As well as the towns of the A20, I wanted to take in the areas under the Dartford Bridge (I had heard tales of a gargantuan pylon down there that I wanted to investigate). My plan was to get out there quickly on public transport then slowly work my way back into London. The quickest way was to get a train from King’s Cross along the brand new High Speed 1 line to Ebbsfleet International, out there somewhere in the Thames Esturay. From here I would walk to the Dartford Crossing, then up the Thames, taking the River Darent into the upper M20 corridor. From here I would work my way through south-east London, back home. So, early on Friday morning, I was hurled out of London and onto flat eluvial planes of the Thames Esturay… EBBSFLEET INTERNATIONAL What I came to realise about Ebbsfleet, is that not only is it not a place that lives up to the grandness implied in “International”, it isn’t actually a place at all. After being the only person to alight from the train here, I wonder out of the station into a barren landscape of endless empty car parks. I eventually get my barrings, and pass under a railway bridge and into Northfleet, an old dock town on the outskirts of Gravesend. As local Danielle, who worked in The Plough pub (now greasy spoon Golden Grill), put it in a 2008 interview to the BBC “There is no Ebbsfleet, it’s a train station and that’s it. That’s all Ebbsfleet is. There is no Ebbsfleet”. Ebbsfleet is in fact a planned development of 40000 new homes on brownfield site in the vicinity of Northfleet. Already in places there are veins of yellow houses worming their way through the brownfield. I follow a sign pointing me towards the Thames Path, behind some warehouses. Getting narrower, hope I don’t meet anyone. Eventually, I can take a passage on the left which opens out onto the docks, but passage is boarded off with silver sheet metal and signs “footpath closed, WARNING do not enter”. I see the huge bodies of decaying dockyard cranes behind the awning, suddenly I’m engulfed with an intense sense of agoraphobic doom…I try to control the panic and head back into Northfleet. This feeling is one that I get again at various points in this landscape - it is not one designed on the human scale, everything is massive - huge trucks, collosal tankers, vast open spaces, towering bridges and pylons. I head out west across the bridge and into Swanscombe, another perculiar Esturary town, and descend towards the Thames into an expansive landscape of rubble and weeds… THAMES GATEWAY Ahead near the river I can see a pylon. It looks close, but it’s an optical illusion: this pylon is four times more massive than any I’ve ever seen. When I finally reach the base, I am standing next to something resembling the Eiffel Tower. On the far bank, there is it’s twin, with thick electrical cables connecting the two high above the river. Onwards up stream to Greenhithe, past Ingress Abbey - built 1833, redeveloped by Crest circa 2002 (this is Deep Thames Gateway territory), the QEII bridge is getting ever closer. Eventually I am under the bridge, and again I am feeling like an ant about to be crushed. High above I hear the sound of endless streams of Tesco lorries vaulting the Thames. All I have for company down here is some rascist graffiti at the base of the concrete superstructure. Moving on, I pass the Littlebrook Oil Fired Power Station and glimpse a fox through the mesh fence adorned with signs warning away those who have come in connection with the “Camp For Climate Action”. On the other side of the river I can see a massive tanker docked at Purfleet. There is a continuous stream of lorries surfacing from the hold. I watch for what seems like hours, transfixed, what on Earth could be inside all those containers? Coffins full of earth? Finally I move on, though the lorries continue. Further upstream I come across a guy fishing; broad, bald, pink shirt, large hands. His wife is set back from the river sun bathing. This seems like a nice spot for a leisurely bit of fishing, though I wonder why he’s the one here? A few yards upstream I find my answer: the infamous Southern Outfall, where everyone’s shit from Brixton to Barnehurst is spewed out into the Thames. Further up river my path is blocked by the introusion of the river Darent, it’s flood defenses visible over the flat landscape. I cut inland across the flood plains, now in the heat of the day, and stumble upon some strange decaying concrete structures - reminents of some by-gone industrial process? THE CRAYS Having crossed the Darent I take a path passed a field full of junk being grazed by a couple of miserable donkies. I follow the Cray, a tidal tributary of the Darent choked with grey silt, past breaker’s yards, through Crayford and eventually come out in the grounds of Hall Place (founded 1537). The gardens were very fine indeed, and I took a much needed rest in the hot houses. Onwards then to Bexley, and suddenly out into the countryside - I pass wondering chickens, riding schools, now into woods. I emerge on a high point on rural Parsonage Lane - in the distance I see a great road crossing the wide valley - the A20? Yes! So I am here, down here, down in that strange vale - I’ve done it, I have travelled to other Worlds! I can see myself on the bridge, starring out of the passenger seat. I worry that if we make eye contact the universe may implode, so I quickly dive behind a hedgerow and shelter until the vehicle is out of view. Unsettled by my encounter I hot-foot it to Foot’s Cray, where I take refuge in the Deep Bar &amp;amp; Restaurant - a local hangout for Deep Topographers. Restored, I head down the A224 Cray Road only to be confronted by an impassable zone of roundabouts and roadside thickets - I have finally reached the A20. As a try to find a way through, wafts of punjent marajuana smoke emenate from an adjacent traveller site. Alas, there is no way through, and I am forced to trek west up the hard shoulder of the Sidcup-Bypass for about half a mile. I notice details that are not attainable at 60 mph: strange mock Tudor dwellings that can only be reached directly from the road side, unknown nature reserves (Scadbury Park). Finally I reach dry land at the Junction with the A222, work my way inland to MAIN ROAD, a long road taking me into further unknown suburbs. FURTHER UNKNOWN SUBURBS Somewhere on my trudge along here I pass into a trance…somewhere between New Eltham and Mottingham I am suddenly struck with hunger. The options aren’t looking great. I settle for an Indian take-away near the petrol station. My feet are sore now and the sun is starting to retreat. Huddled under a raincoat, I tuck in to my fluorescent chicken-tikka massala in some municipal park, hoping no one sees me. I have a quick check of the A-Z and head on through Eltham. Eventually I see something familiar - the Kidbrooke Estate. I have come at an interesting time - the whole estate is under massive redevelopment - the old Moon base is being replaced by something more hi-tech - dwellings fit for 21st century living. There are only a few of the old buildings left standing. This place doesn’t feel safe, - I pick my way through half demolished council blocks, searching for a way out - I take my chances down a narrow allyway hoping I don’t meet anyone. I’m nearly at the out when my heart sinks - I hear voices coming from the other end - with no choice I plough on. As emerge from the other end ready to run, I almost collide with two prams being pushed by a pair of yummy mummys. WORMHOLE I seem to have fallen through some sort of worm-hole and landed in Hampstead. The streets are lined with Jaguars and 4x4s. The houses are detached and have columns. Where am I? As I walk down the leavy street, I consult my A-Z. It appears I am in Blackheath. The Highgate of the South. As twilight approaches, I climb up to the heath, another site connected to the Camp For Climate Action, and gaze out across the city. I am planning to meet a friend in Brixton Market for a drink later. Having come this far by foot, I resolve to make Brixton by 9pm. I set off west down Shooter’s Hill, sticking to the main road all the way as it lacings through the inner-city districts of South London. As I recall, somewhere around Deptford a large blister on my ankle popped, considerably slowing progress. Somehow I limped on, and reached the market before 10pm, being just over 30 miles from Northfleet. In the days afterwards, both of the nails on my big toes turned black. I have since bought new walking boots.</summary></entry></feed>